Guide to the Lake Mohonk Mountain House records, 1870-1968.
Lake Mohonk Mountain House records, 1870-1968.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lake Mohonk Mountain House records, 1870-1968.
2835
Lake Mohonk Mountain House.
80.0 cubic ft.
Correspondence, bills, bank statements, payroll records, insurance politices, guest accounts, ledgers, farm records, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of Lake Mohonk Mountain House, a resort hotel in the Shawangunk Mountains near New Paltz, New York, owned and operated by the Smileys, a Quaker family. Albert Smiley bought a tavern near Lake Mohonk and 280 acres, including the lake, in 1869.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Lake Mohonk Mountain House is a resort hotel in the Shawangunk Mountains near New Paltz, New York, owned and operated by the Smileys, a Quaker family. Albert Smiley bought a tavern near Lake Mohonk and 280 acres, including the lake, in 1869.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters and letterbooks, including house correspondence, Smiley and Benjamin S. Helmer correspondence; bills and bank statements; employee time books and payrolls; insurance policies; guest accounts and ledgers. Also includes records and accounts concerning provisions and maintenance, workman's compensation and unemployment, the golf course and tennis courts, dining room, laundry, and power house. Also, Brook Farm and Spring Farm cattle and milk production records, guest records and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lake Mohonk Mountain House.; Helmer, Benjamin S.; Smiley family.; Smiley, Albert.; Smiley, Alfred.
Subjects:
Hotel management.; Hotels--Employees.; Hotels--Finance.; Resorts--Employees.; Resorts--Finance.; Resorts.
Form and Genre Terms:
Ledgers.; Insurance policies.; Bills (financial).; Guest registers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- B letters 1905, P letters 1905, 1905 letters (Box 1)
- 1908 letters, 1915 letters, 1921 letters (Box 2)
- House Correspondence 1913-1914 C-J (Box 3)
- House Correspondence 1913-1914 K-P (Box 4)
- House Correspondence 1913-1914 Q-W (Box 5)
- House Correspondence 1915 A-D (Box 6)
- House Correspondence 1915 E-K (Box 7)
- House Correspondence 1915 M-Q (Box 8)
- House Correspondence 1915 Q-V (Box 9)
- Correspondence, Smiley 1916-1925 (Box 10)
- Benjamin S. Helmer Correspondence 1922 (Box 11)
- Benjamin S. Helmer Correspondence 1913-1920 (Box 12)
- Benjamin S. Helmer Correspondence 1933-1937 (Box 13)
- Form letters and miscellaneous correspondence, 1918-1965 (Box 14)
- Job inquiries, Bellboy records, miscellaneous correspondence, Post office information, Railroad information, 1905-1911 (Box 15)
- Gold Records and Unemployment Records, 1953-1971 (Box 16)
- Guest Accounting - telephone 1964, and night auditor's reports 1964-1966 (Box 17)
- Bills, Registration sheet, banking notes, blank forms, sundry, 1883-1968 (Box 18)
- Internal accounts (Box 19)
- Charge slips 1944-1959 (Box 20)
- Workmen's Compensation, Room charges 1954-1963 (Box 21)
- Bank Statements 1961 (Box 22)
- Bills 1899 F-K, Bank Statements 1937, Telephone bills, 1910 A-F (Box 23)
- Bills 1910 G-Z, 1911 (Box 24)
- Bills 1912 (Box 25)
- House Bills, 1905-1915 (Box 26)
- Mohonk Salesrooms bills 1912, Western Union Bills 1917, Freight bills 1905, 1912, 1913 (Box 27)
- Bills 1913 (Box 28)
- Bills 1915, Room charges 1954 (Box 29)
- Dining room records 1909-1948 (Box 30)
- Spring Farm Records, rates and accommodations of other resorts, Milk Production Sheets, 3 wage ledgers 1894-1913 (Box 31)
- Cattle Records 1943-1953 (Box 32)
- Insurance records, 1926-1936, Kleinehill, Brook and Spring Farm Cattle and Milk Production Records and correspondence 1906-1915 (Box 33)
- Brook Farm Records 1932-1939, 1950-1956, Spring Farm 1932, guest records 1955-1965 (Box 34)
- Employee Time Books mostly 1950's, few 1890's (Box 35)
- Employee Time Books mostly 1958-1965, few 1888-1899 (Box 36)
- Employee Time Books 1941-1965 (Box 37)
- Employee Time Books 1915-1960's (Box 38)
- Employee Time Books 1915-1960's (Box 39)
- Employee Time Books 1915-1960's (Box 39a)
- Employee Time Books 1909-1943 (Box 40)
- Invoices 1892, purchase records of newspapers 1898, Post Office 1893-1896, school accounts 1922 (Box 41)
- 4 editions and one duplicate of the History of Mohonk Book, brochures for Lake Mohonk Mountain House, anniversary booklet (Box 42)
- Room Occupancy Record (work sheet) for the years 1932-1940
- Guest Account Ledgers for the years 1916, 1919-1922
- Insurance policies boxed in chronological order by expiration date
  - 1920-1925 (Box 43)
  - 1930-1932 (Box 44)
  - 1933 (Box 45)
  - 1934 (Box 46)
  - 1935 (Box 47)
  - 1936-1938 (Box 48)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 49)
  - 1939-1942 (Box 50)
  - 1943, 1 policy for 1946, 1949 and auto policies for 1950-1956 (Box 51)
  - 1950-1953 (Box 52)
  - 1954-1956, 1958-1962 (Box 53)
- Rustic Work 1919-1947 (Box 54)
- Dining Room and Meal Books 1916-1946, Laundry 1915-1927 (Box 55)
- Transportation and Garage time books 1909-1945, Stewards 1917-1921, 1942-1946, Tennis Courts 1919-1920, Bowling Alley 1941-1942, John Yeaple wage books 1918 (Box 56)
- Brook Farm, Spring Farm 1922-1935, Powerhouse 1915-1947, Carpenters 1920-1924, Phil Countryman 1921 (Box 57)
- Painters 1916-1925, 1945, Guest Housekeepters 1904-1928, 1937-1941, Bell Boys 1918-1925, Ira Smith 1918 (Box 58)
- Hugh Smiley wage books 1915-1919, Francis Smiley 1920, Rachel Smiley 1939, other wage books 1914-1935 (Box 59)
- Miscellaneous wage books and chores 1907-1933 (Box 60)
- 1 vol. of Guest charges 1906 and miscellaneous guest bills 1930-1965 (Box 61)